{
    "id": "4931541278f34448a1ae6969a1817682",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The boys were playing games when it ………………………. raining.",
            "description": "We usually use the simple past for an action that happens in the middle of another action. ",
            "answers": [
                "was starting",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You were watching TV when I ……………………… for my exam.",
            "description": "Continuous tenses are used to talk about two actions that were progressing at the same time. ",
            "answers": [
                "prepared",
                "am preparing",
                "was preparing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The phone ………………………. while I was cooking dinner.",
            "description": "We usually use the simple past for an action that happens in the middle of another action. ",
            "answers": [
                "rings",
                "rang",
                "was ringing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How long ……………………… a social activist?",
            "description": "Perfect tenses are usually used to talk about duration. ",
            "answers": [
                "have you been",
                "are you",
                "were you"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………….. each other for a long time.",
            "description": "We normally use perfect tenses with since and for. ",
            "answers": [
                "knew",
                "are knowing",
                "have known"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………… nothing from all the wars in history.",
            "description": "When there is no reference to any specific past time, we usually use the present perfect to talk about finished actions or situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "are learning",
                "have learnt",
                "learnt"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… well for the exam.",
            "description": "When there is no reference to any specific past time, we usually use the present perfect to talk about finished actions or situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "prepared",
                "have prepared",
                "had prepared"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. well for the exam, yet I failed.",
            "description": "The past tense in the second clause clearly indicates that the reference is to the past time. ",
            "answers": [
                "prepared",
                "have prepared",
                "was preparing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher ……………………… an interesting question in the class yesterday.",
            "description": "When there is a definite past time reference we use the simple past to talk about finished actions or situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "asks",
                "has asked",
                "asked"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I looked around but I ……………………. anyone.",
            "description": "The reference is to the past time here. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't find",
                "hadn't found",
                "don't find"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She threw a glass at me, but ……………………",
            "description": "When one verb is in the past tense, the other verbs will most probably also be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "was missing",
                "missed",
                "had missed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don’t hurry, you …………………. the train.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will miss",
                "would miss",
                "missed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}